<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: non-technical | DevOp's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/blog/categories/non-technical/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-18T19:51:54+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://jakshi.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[jakshi]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2014 year sum up]]></title>
    <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2015/01/01/2014-year-sum-up/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-01T07:52:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2015/01/01/2014-year-sum-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>5 important things that I did this year:

<ul>
<li>Got Married.</li>
<li>Learnt how to <a href="/images/me_on_the_motorcycle.jpg">drive a motorcycle</a>. Bought my first motorcycle.</li>
<li>live whole year in Asia, in Thailand, Krabi and Malaysia, Cyberjaya during 2013/2014 year.</li>
<li>Finish 2 <a href="https://www.coursera.org/">Coursera</a> courses <a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/webapplications">Web Application Architectures</a> and <a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/behavioralecon">A Beginner's Guide to Irrational Behavior</a></li>
<li>I learnt TDD approach to writing code, and applied it in practice. It's just awesome.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<!-- more -->


<ul>
<li>Most interesting/inspiring people I met this year:

<ul>
<li>Kaveh Mousavi Zamani - Software developer and DevOps engineer. He tought me that simplicity is a virtue for DevOps and complexity can kill your infrastructure projects.</li>
<li>Shuwn Yuan Tee - Software developer and DBA. She reminded me that you should never stop learning. It's amazing how much can people learn if he/she doesn't waste his/her time.</li>
<li>Dmitriy Paramonov - Entrepreneur. He showed me that it's more profitable to sell tools/supplies that help other people to do their work, than do that work by yourself.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>people that change my way to thinking this year:

<ul>
<li>Stephen Nelson-Smith - he tought me a lot about TDD. It changes my whole thinking about software development (in a good way). I understand that you can get confidence in your code.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Two new hobbies this year:

<ul>
<li>Learning programming on <a href="https://www.codeschool.com">codeschool</a></li>
<li>Learn how to maintain and customizing my motorcycle</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Two might-have-been dream in this year:

<ul>
<li>Buy a car</li>
<li>Travel to Indonesia</li>
<li>Travel to South-America</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h1>What did not go well</h1>

<p>I:</p>

<ul>
<li>still have not much money so a lot of plans still postponed</li>
<li>often find hard to concentrate on work</li>
<li>still not very good in choosing priorities</li>
<li>spend a lot of time on garabage things, like reading blogs, news and so on useless stuff</li>
<li>don't pay enough attention to sport activity</li>
<li>I spent a lot of time learning  ไทย, but I still not even close to speaking this language.</li>
<li>I got two good job offers simultaneously and It was a frustrating experience, to choose between two interesting projects.</li>
</ul>


<h1>What went well</h1>

<p>I:</p>

<ul>
<li>I traveled a lot. I lived one month in Malaysia, Cyberjaya. also I traveled by car to Penang island in Malaysia again. I traveled to Thailand, ko Samui (~300 km) on my motorcycle.</li>
<li>I did more programming, My developer skills became better. I learnt some RoR, Javascript basics and my Ruby is almost fluent.</li>
<li>I leant a lot about unit and integration testing, TDD and applying this to writing chef cookbooks.</li>
<li>Enhance my <a href="http://www.opscode.com/chef/">opscode chef</a> cooking skills even more.</li>
<li>I bought a notebook with FullHD IPS matrix, why I didn't to this before? It's just great.</li>
</ul>


<h1>What I would like to achieve in new year?</h1>

<ul>
<li>I want to buy and learn to drive more powerful motorcycle, 50+ h.p.</li>
<li>I want to start programming RoR and/or javascript for money</li>
<li>I want to have stable 50$ per hour rates</li>
<li>I want to start speaking on a new language</li>
<li>I want to visit 3 new foreign countries</li>
<li>I want to start rock climbing again</li>
<li>I want to make my eyesight better than this year.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2013 year sum up]]></title>
    <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2013/12/30/2013-year-sum-up/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-30T11:52:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2013/12/30/2013-year-sum-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>5 important things that I did this year:

<ul>
<li>Learn how to drive a car.</li>
<li>go to second big travel to Asia, living in Thailand, Krabi during 2013/2014 winter.</li>
<li>go for two short travels to Malaysia. By plane from Ko Samui to Kuala Lumpur, by car from Krabi to Penang island.</li>
<li>go for short travel to Germany.</li>
<li>Finish <a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/introfinance">Introduction to Finance course</a> on <a href="https://www.coursera.org/">Coursera</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<!-- more -->


<ul>
<li>Most interesting/inspiring people I met this year:

<ul>
<li>Sergey Balbeko - IT infrastructure developer, hipster. He shows me how strong you need to crave for new knowledge. That it's very important to constantly develope yourself.</li>
<li>Anzhela Piage - Entrepreneur, psychologist. She shows me how important to think about win-win strategy not only with people, but with all the world around us.</li>
<li>Evgeniy Kuzmenko - Businessman. Man that shows me how important to be optimistic and persistent.</li>
<li>Tanya Shorokhova - Art director. She inspires me to see <a href="/images/owl.jpg">owls around us</a>.</li>
<li>Oscar - millionaire from the sratch. Man that prove the idea that win-win strategy better than win-lose one. Also confirm the point that to be rich you need to work a lot and be very persistent.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>people that change my way to thinking this year:

<ul>
<li>Sergey Balbeko - He inspires me to be more open-minded about IT world and I learnt that social interaction is important (more important that I thought before).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Two new hobbies this year:

<ul>
<li>Learning programming on codecademy</li>
<li>Learning Thai language</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Two might-have-been dream in this year:

<ul>
<li>Buy an apartment</li>
<li>Trip to Europe</li>
<li>Travel to South-America</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h1>What did not go well</h1>

<p>I:</p>

<ul>
<li>still have not much money so a lot of plans still postponed</li>
<li>often find hard to concentrate on work</li>
<li>still not very good in choosing priorities</li>
<li>spend a lot of time on garabage things, like reading blogs, news and so on useless stuff</li>
<li>don't pay enough attention to sport activity</li>
</ul>


<h1>What went well</h1>

<p>I:</p>

<ul>
<li>learnt how to <a href="/images/me_and_a_car.jpg">drive a car</a>, I drove sedan, crossover, pick-up. In city, town, rural roads, highways.</li>
<li>traveled a lot, it was life changing experience! I traveled more than last year, because I can drive a car now. I was in several national parks in Krabi province and traveled by car to Penang island in Malaysia.</li>
<li>was programming more, My developer skills became better, I learnt basics of Python, Javascript and my Ruby is almost fluent already.</li>
<li>I learnt basics of CSS and HTML.</li>
<li>finished <a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/introfinance">Introduction to Finance course</a> on <a href="https://www.coursera.org/">Coursera</a> and got that to learn good - you need to enjoy it, learning mood is important.</li>
<li>Enhance my <a href="http://www.opscode.com/chef/">opscode chef</a> cooking skills even more.</li>
<li>learnt how to read ไทย, and now I know about 600 Thai words. Though I understand now that it's not a sprint - it's a marathon.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Winter in Thailand or from idea to reality: Part III - Visas]]></title>
    <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2013/01/19/winter-in-thailand-or-from-idea-to-reality-part-iii-visas/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-19T23:31:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2013/01/19/winter-in-thailand-or-from-idea-to-reality-part-iii-visas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Intro</h1>

<p>I have air tickets to Thailand now, but that's not all. Now I need visa to Thailand.</p>

<p>I will tell about getting visa to Thailand for Ukrainian citizens.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h1>Types of Thailand visas for Ukrainians</h1>

<ul>
<li>Visa on arrival, 15 days: you can get it in the airport. Sometimes you can be asked to prove that you have enough money and have air ticket from Thailand.</li>
<li>Single entry tourist visa, 2 monthes + can be prolong for 1 month for 1900 Baht: You need to process it in advance.</li>
<li>Double entry tourist visa, 2+1 monthes, fly out of Thailand, fly back and then again 2+1 monthes.: You need to process it in advance.</li>
<li>Business visa: about 1 year, I don't look into this visa a lot becasue you need to have some buisness in Thailand.</li>
<li>Education visa: about 1 year, Nod bad, but you need to learn something in Thailand and pay money to some Thailand's educational institution.</li>
</ul>


<h1>Which visa to choose?</h1>

<ul>
<li>Visa to arrival? definitely no, we need to stay for several monthes.</li>
<li>Tourist visa? Sounds good.</li>
<li>Buisness visa? I haven't buisness in Thailand and don't plan to create one.</li>
<li>Education visa? not bad, but more expensive than tourist visa (from 20000 Baht per year). And of course you will need spend time for learning.</li>
</ul>


<p>So after some thoughts I chose double entry tourist's visa.</p>

<h1>Processing a visa</h1>

<p>I do a little trick for proccess Thailand visa easier - I outsource this work to Travel Agency :)
Of course each visa cost more for me(170$ instead of 90$), but I saved a lot of time and brain cells.</p>

<p>Also Travel Agency help us with processing medical insurrance for Thailand, it costs us about 150$ per person.</p>

<p>I provided following documents to process visas:
- Foreign passport
- Reference about your bank account state (you need to have more than 600$ on your bank account)
- Printed air tickets
- Insurance vouchers
- Reference from work that we have work place in Ukraine
- two 3x4 cm photos</p>

<p>I gave these documents to travel agency and in a week have my foreign passports with visa back.</p>

<p>if you proccess double-entry visas usually you need to provide airticket to Thailand and back for both entries. I didn't have tickets for flying out of Thailand after 3 month (first part of double entry visa). I plan to decide later where to go. Luckily Travel agency where I proccessed visas resolve this for me, they booked additional tickets, get the visa for me and then cancel additional tickets. So I don't need to think about <where to travel after 3 month in Thailand>  beforehand. As I got actually you can even don't buy return ticket if you use travel agency service for proccess visas.</p>

<p>Okey, now I have our airticket, I have visa.</p>

<p>So I need to think thorougly which stuff to get with us, and even more thourougly which stuff don't. I need to plan the travel, book hotel and gather info about how to live good in Thailand. I need prepare for trip.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2012 year sum up]]></title>
    <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2012/12/31/2012-year-sum-up/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-31T16:34:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2012/12/31/2012-year-sum-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Two important things that I did this year:

<ul>
<li>Went to big travel to Asia, living in Thailand during 2012/2013 winter.</li>
<li>Went for short travel to Greece and UAE.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<!-- more -->


<ul>
<li>Most interesting/inspiring people I met this year:

<ul>
<li>Taxi driver Ali in UAE who can talk on 7 languages very good and knows about 15 languages not very well (but still can speak them)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Two people that change my way to thinking this year:

<ul>
<li>Taxi driver Ali, I got that it's not so hard to know a lot of languages, you need just speak a lot.</li>
<li>Stephen Nelson Smith, He tought me a lot about IT infra management and software development.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Two new hobbies this year:

<ul>
<li>Snorkeling</li>
<li>Bycicle riding</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Two might-have-been dream in this year:

<ul>
<li>Buy own apartment</li>
<li>Learn how to build sites with RoR</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h1>What did not go well</h1>

<p>I:</p>

<ul>
<li>still have not much money so a lot of plans still postponed</li>
<li>often find hard to concentrate on work</li>
<li>still not very good in choosing priorities</li>
<li>spend a lot of time on garabage things, like reading blogs, news and so on useless stuff</li>
<li>don't pay enough attention to sport activity</li>
</ul>


<h1>What went well</h1>

<p>I:</p>

<ul>
<li>traveled a lot, it was life changing experience!</li>
<li>was programming more, My developer skills became better, I learn basics of Python and some Ruby too.</li>
<li>finished statistics course on <a href="https://www.coursera.org/">Coursera</a> and got again that learning is fun.</li>
<li>became quite good in writing <a href="http://www.opscode.com/chef/">opscode chef</a> recipes/cookbooks.</li>
<li>began to ride a bycicle again after 10 years of neglecting and was snorkeling in Mediterranean sea.</li>
<li>learnt how to <a href="/images/me_on_the_motor_scooter.jpg">drive motor scooter</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Winter in Thailand or from idea to reality: Part II - Air tickets]]></title>
    <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/winter-in-thailand-or-from-idea-to-reality-part-ii-air-tickets/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-15T13:02:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/winter-in-thailand-or-from-idea-to-reality-part-ii-air-tickets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Intro</h1>

<p>So I need to buy air tickets to Thailand. After some thoughts we decide to buy air tickets to Bagkok, spent there several days, and then move to Ko Samui.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h1>Where to find cheapest ones?</h1>

<p>I doubt that I'll say something new, but earlier you buy tickets - the cheaper they will get.
Because:</p>

<ul>
<li>most cheap tickets end up first.</li>
<li>most companies give you discount if you buy tickets in advance.</li>
</ul>


<p>Also you can try to search on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_low-cost_airlines">sites of low cost airways</a>, but this will need much more thorough planning of your trip, because low cost airlines are less agile then usual airlines.</p>

<p>Example of low cost airways for Thailand: <a href="http://www.airasia.com/my/en/home.page">AirAsia</a> or <a href="http://www.nokair.com/nokconnext/aspx/Index.aspx?currlang=en-US">NokAir</a>.</p>

<p>I use <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a> to search for cheapest tickets. I bought tickets not early, so they cost me a lot - 900$ per person from Ukraine to Thailand and back.</p>

<p>After I found tickets on <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a>, <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a> provide me a choice of sites where I can book them.</p>

<p>I choose <a href="http://www.orbitz.com/">Orbitz</a>. it was a good choice. <a href="http://www.orbitz.com/">Orbitz</a> worked very well, there wasn't any problems.</p>

<p>I bought tickets from Austrian Airways from Khrakov to Bangkok with one connection in Vienna.</p>

<p>Flight from Kharkov to Vienna was very good. Flight from Vienna to Bangkok in Boing 777 wasn't so comfortable. They have very small chairs in those Boing 777 :)</p>

<p>btw For Ukrainian traveler there's a good route to fly to Dubai, and then fly from Dubai to Bangkok. Looking back I see that idea with connection in Vienna wasn't a best idea. Actually we flight from Kharkov to Vienna in reverse direction from Bangkok, so then we should fly 10 hours to Bangkok.</p>

<h1>Running a few step forward.</h1>

<p>Later I use <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a> again to search for and book tickets to Ko Samui from Bangkok. There was a lot of problems with booking tickets with <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a>. so I don't recommend to book tickets with <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a> itself, use it only for searching.</p>

<p>Problems was:</p>

<ul>
<li>They confirm booking</li>
<li>HOLD money on creditcard</li>
<li>Then canceled booking</li>
<li>Money on creditcard stayed on HOLD for 30 days</li>
</ul>


<p>I especially don't like the last point.</p>

<p>I booked tickets that <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a> cannot book for me on site of air company that make flight - it was <a href="http://www.bangkokair.com/eng">Bangkok Airways</a>, there wasn't any problems.</p>

<p>So I got the air tickets, and now <a href="/blog/2013/01/19/winter-in-thailand-or-from-idea-to-reality-part-iii-visas/">I needed to get visa to Thailand.</a></p>

<h1>Further reading</h1>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.orbitz.com/">Orbitz</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
