<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: sum_up | DevOp's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/blog/categories/sum-up/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-18T19:51:54+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://jakshi.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[jakshi]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2014 year sum up]]></title>
    <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2015/01/01/2014-year-sum-up/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-01T07:52:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2015/01/01/2014-year-sum-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>5 important things that I did this year:

<ul>
<li>Got Married.</li>
<li>Learnt how to <a href="/images/me_on_the_motorcycle.jpg">drive a motorcycle</a>. Bought my first motorcycle.</li>
<li>live whole year in Asia, in Thailand, Krabi and Malaysia, Cyberjaya during 2013/2014 year.</li>
<li>Finish 2 <a href="https://www.coursera.org/">Coursera</a> courses <a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/webapplications">Web Application Architectures</a> and <a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/behavioralecon">A Beginner's Guide to Irrational Behavior</a></li>
<li>I learnt TDD approach to writing code, and applied it in practice. It's just awesome.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<!-- more -->


<ul>
<li>Most interesting/inspiring people I met this year:

<ul>
<li>Kaveh Mousavi Zamani - Software developer and DevOps engineer. He tought me that simplicity is a virtue for DevOps and complexity can kill your infrastructure projects.</li>
<li>Shuwn Yuan Tee - Software developer and DBA. She reminded me that you should never stop learning. It's amazing how much can people learn if he/she doesn't waste his/her time.</li>
<li>Dmitriy Paramonov - Entrepreneur. He showed me that it's more profitable to sell tools/supplies that help other people to do their work, than do that work by yourself.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>people that change my way to thinking this year:

<ul>
<li>Stephen Nelson-Smith - he tought me a lot about TDD. It changes my whole thinking about software development (in a good way). I understand that you can get confidence in your code.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Two new hobbies this year:

<ul>
<li>Learning programming on <a href="https://www.codeschool.com">codeschool</a></li>
<li>Learn how to maintain and customizing my motorcycle</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Two might-have-been dream in this year:

<ul>
<li>Buy a car</li>
<li>Travel to Indonesia</li>
<li>Travel to South-America</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h1>What did not go well</h1>

<p>I:</p>

<ul>
<li>still have not much money so a lot of plans still postponed</li>
<li>often find hard to concentrate on work</li>
<li>still not very good in choosing priorities</li>
<li>spend a lot of time on garabage things, like reading blogs, news and so on useless stuff</li>
<li>don't pay enough attention to sport activity</li>
<li>I spent a lot of time learning  ไทย, but I still not even close to speaking this language.</li>
<li>I got two good job offers simultaneously and It was a frustrating experience, to choose between two interesting projects.</li>
</ul>


<h1>What went well</h1>

<p>I:</p>

<ul>
<li>I traveled a lot. I lived one month in Malaysia, Cyberjaya. also I traveled by car to Penang island in Malaysia again. I traveled to Thailand, ko Samui (~300 km) on my motorcycle.</li>
<li>I did more programming, My developer skills became better. I learnt some RoR, Javascript basics and my Ruby is almost fluent.</li>
<li>I leant a lot about unit and integration testing, TDD and applying this to writing chef cookbooks.</li>
<li>Enhance my <a href="http://www.opscode.com/chef/">opscode chef</a> cooking skills even more.</li>
<li>I bought a notebook with FullHD IPS matrix, why I didn't to this before? It's just great.</li>
</ul>


<h1>What I would like to achieve in new year?</h1>

<ul>
<li>I want to buy and learn to drive more powerful motorcycle, 50+ h.p.</li>
<li>I want to start programming RoR and/or javascript for money</li>
<li>I want to have stable 50$ per hour rates</li>
<li>I want to start speaking on a new language</li>
<li>I want to visit 3 new foreign countries</li>
<li>I want to start rock climbing again</li>
<li>I want to make my eyesight better than this year.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2013 year sum up]]></title>
    <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2013/12/30/2013-year-sum-up/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-30T11:52:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2013/12/30/2013-year-sum-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>5 important things that I did this year:

<ul>
<li>Learn how to drive a car.</li>
<li>go to second big travel to Asia, living in Thailand, Krabi during 2013/2014 winter.</li>
<li>go for two short travels to Malaysia. By plane from Ko Samui to Kuala Lumpur, by car from Krabi to Penang island.</li>
<li>go for short travel to Germany.</li>
<li>Finish <a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/introfinance">Introduction to Finance course</a> on <a href="https://www.coursera.org/">Coursera</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<!-- more -->


<ul>
<li>Most interesting/inspiring people I met this year:

<ul>
<li>Sergey Balbeko - IT infrastructure developer, hipster. He shows me how strong you need to crave for new knowledge. That it's very important to constantly develope yourself.</li>
<li>Anzhela Piage - Entrepreneur, psychologist. She shows me how important to think about win-win strategy not only with people, but with all the world around us.</li>
<li>Evgeniy Kuzmenko - Businessman. Man that shows me how important to be optimistic and persistent.</li>
<li>Tanya Shorokhova - Art director. She inspires me to see <a href="/images/owl.jpg">owls around us</a>.</li>
<li>Oscar - millionaire from the sratch. Man that prove the idea that win-win strategy better than win-lose one. Also confirm the point that to be rich you need to work a lot and be very persistent.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>people that change my way to thinking this year:

<ul>
<li>Sergey Balbeko - He inspires me to be more open-minded about IT world and I learnt that social interaction is important (more important that I thought before).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Two new hobbies this year:

<ul>
<li>Learning programming on codecademy</li>
<li>Learning Thai language</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Two might-have-been dream in this year:

<ul>
<li>Buy an apartment</li>
<li>Trip to Europe</li>
<li>Travel to South-America</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h1>What did not go well</h1>

<p>I:</p>

<ul>
<li>still have not much money so a lot of plans still postponed</li>
<li>often find hard to concentrate on work</li>
<li>still not very good in choosing priorities</li>
<li>spend a lot of time on garabage things, like reading blogs, news and so on useless stuff</li>
<li>don't pay enough attention to sport activity</li>
</ul>


<h1>What went well</h1>

<p>I:</p>

<ul>
<li>learnt how to <a href="/images/me_and_a_car.jpg">drive a car</a>, I drove sedan, crossover, pick-up. In city, town, rural roads, highways.</li>
<li>traveled a lot, it was life changing experience! I traveled more than last year, because I can drive a car now. I was in several national parks in Krabi province and traveled by car to Penang island in Malaysia.</li>
<li>was programming more, My developer skills became better, I learnt basics of Python, Javascript and my Ruby is almost fluent already.</li>
<li>I learnt basics of CSS and HTML.</li>
<li>finished <a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/introfinance">Introduction to Finance course</a> on <a href="https://www.coursera.org/">Coursera</a> and got that to learn good - you need to enjoy it, learning mood is important.</li>
<li>Enhance my <a href="http://www.opscode.com/chef/">opscode chef</a> cooking skills even more.</li>
<li>learnt how to read ไทย, and now I know about 600 Thai words. Though I understand now that it's not a sprint - it's a marathon.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2012 year sum up]]></title>
    <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2012/12/31/2012-year-sum-up/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-31T16:34:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2012/12/31/2012-year-sum-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Two important things that I did this year:

<ul>
<li>Went to big travel to Asia, living in Thailand during 2012/2013 winter.</li>
<li>Went for short travel to Greece and UAE.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<!-- more -->


<ul>
<li>Most interesting/inspiring people I met this year:

<ul>
<li>Taxi driver Ali in UAE who can talk on 7 languages very good and knows about 15 languages not very well (but still can speak them)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Two people that change my way to thinking this year:

<ul>
<li>Taxi driver Ali, I got that it's not so hard to know a lot of languages, you need just speak a lot.</li>
<li>Stephen Nelson Smith, He tought me a lot about IT infra management and software development.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Two new hobbies this year:

<ul>
<li>Snorkeling</li>
<li>Bycicle riding</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Two might-have-been dream in this year:

<ul>
<li>Buy own apartment</li>
<li>Learn how to build sites with RoR</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h1>What did not go well</h1>

<p>I:</p>

<ul>
<li>still have not much money so a lot of plans still postponed</li>
<li>often find hard to concentrate on work</li>
<li>still not very good in choosing priorities</li>
<li>spend a lot of time on garabage things, like reading blogs, news and so on useless stuff</li>
<li>don't pay enough attention to sport activity</li>
</ul>


<h1>What went well</h1>

<p>I:</p>

<ul>
<li>traveled a lot, it was life changing experience!</li>
<li>was programming more, My developer skills became better, I learn basics of Python and some Ruby too.</li>
<li>finished statistics course on <a href="https://www.coursera.org/">Coursera</a> and got again that learning is fun.</li>
<li>became quite good in writing <a href="http://www.opscode.com/chef/">opscode chef</a> recipes/cookbooks.</li>
<li>began to ride a bycicle again after 10 years of neglecting and was snorkeling in Mediterranean sea.</li>
<li>learnt how to <a href="/images/me_on_the_motor_scooter.jpg">drive motor scooter</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
