<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: koh samui | DevOp's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/blog/categories/koh-samui/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-18T19:51:54+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://jakshi.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[jakshi]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Winter in Thailand or from idea to reality: Part III - Visas]]></title>
    <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2013/01/19/winter-in-thailand-or-from-idea-to-reality-part-iii-visas/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-19T23:31:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2013/01/19/winter-in-thailand-or-from-idea-to-reality-part-iii-visas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Intro</h1>

<p>I have air tickets to Thailand now, but that's not all. Now I need visa to Thailand.</p>

<p>I will tell about getting visa to Thailand for Ukrainian citizens.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h1>Types of Thailand visas for Ukrainians</h1>

<ul>
<li>Visa on arrival, 15 days: you can get it in the airport. Sometimes you can be asked to prove that you have enough money and have air ticket from Thailand.</li>
<li>Single entry tourist visa, 2 monthes + can be prolong for 1 month for 1900 Baht: You need to process it in advance.</li>
<li>Double entry tourist visa, 2+1 monthes, fly out of Thailand, fly back and then again 2+1 monthes.: You need to process it in advance.</li>
<li>Business visa: about 1 year, I don't look into this visa a lot becasue you need to have some buisness in Thailand.</li>
<li>Education visa: about 1 year, Nod bad, but you need to learn something in Thailand and pay money to some Thailand's educational institution.</li>
</ul>


<h1>Which visa to choose?</h1>

<ul>
<li>Visa to arrival? definitely no, we need to stay for several monthes.</li>
<li>Tourist visa? Sounds good.</li>
<li>Buisness visa? I haven't buisness in Thailand and don't plan to create one.</li>
<li>Education visa? not bad, but more expensive than tourist visa (from 20000 Baht per year). And of course you will need spend time for learning.</li>
</ul>


<p>So after some thoughts I chose double entry tourist's visa.</p>

<h1>Processing a visa</h1>

<p>I do a little trick for proccess Thailand visa easier - I outsource this work to Travel Agency :)
Of course each visa cost more for me(170$ instead of 90$), but I saved a lot of time and brain cells.</p>

<p>Also Travel Agency help us with processing medical insurrance for Thailand, it costs us about 150$ per person.</p>

<p>I provided following documents to process visas:
- Foreign passport
- Reference about your bank account state (you need to have more than 600$ on your bank account)
- Printed air tickets
- Insurance vouchers
- Reference from work that we have work place in Ukraine
- two 3x4 cm photos</p>

<p>I gave these documents to travel agency and in a week have my foreign passports with visa back.</p>

<p>if you proccess double-entry visas usually you need to provide airticket to Thailand and back for both entries. I didn't have tickets for flying out of Thailand after 3 month (first part of double entry visa). I plan to decide later where to go. Luckily Travel agency where I proccessed visas resolve this for me, they booked additional tickets, get the visa for me and then cancel additional tickets. So I don't need to think about <where to travel after 3 month in Thailand>  beforehand. As I got actually you can even don't buy return ticket if you use travel agency service for proccess visas.</p>

<p>Okey, now I have our airticket, I have visa.</p>

<p>So I need to think thorougly which stuff to get with us, and even more thourougly which stuff don't. I need to plan the travel, book hotel and gather info about how to live good in Thailand. I need prepare for trip.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Winter in Thailand or from idea to reality: Part II - Air tickets]]></title>
    <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/winter-in-thailand-or-from-idea-to-reality-part-ii-air-tickets/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-15T13:02:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/winter-in-thailand-or-from-idea-to-reality-part-ii-air-tickets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Intro</h1>

<p>So I need to buy air tickets to Thailand. After some thoughts we decide to buy air tickets to Bagkok, spent there several days, and then move to Ko Samui.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h1>Where to find cheapest ones?</h1>

<p>I doubt that I'll say something new, but earlier you buy tickets - the cheaper they will get.
Because:</p>

<ul>
<li>most cheap tickets end up first.</li>
<li>most companies give you discount if you buy tickets in advance.</li>
</ul>


<p>Also you can try to search on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_low-cost_airlines">sites of low cost airways</a>, but this will need much more thorough planning of your trip, because low cost airlines are less agile then usual airlines.</p>

<p>Example of low cost airways for Thailand: <a href="http://www.airasia.com/my/en/home.page">AirAsia</a> or <a href="http://www.nokair.com/nokconnext/aspx/Index.aspx?currlang=en-US">NokAir</a>.</p>

<p>I use <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a> to search for cheapest tickets. I bought tickets not early, so they cost me a lot - 900$ per person from Ukraine to Thailand and back.</p>

<p>After I found tickets on <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a>, <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a> provide me a choice of sites where I can book them.</p>

<p>I choose <a href="http://www.orbitz.com/">Orbitz</a>. it was a good choice. <a href="http://www.orbitz.com/">Orbitz</a> worked very well, there wasn't any problems.</p>

<p>I bought tickets from Austrian Airways from Khrakov to Bangkok with one connection in Vienna.</p>

<p>Flight from Kharkov to Vienna was very good. Flight from Vienna to Bangkok in Boing 777 wasn't so comfortable. They have very small chairs in those Boing 777 :)</p>

<p>btw For Ukrainian traveler there's a good route to fly to Dubai, and then fly from Dubai to Bangkok. Looking back I see that idea with connection in Vienna wasn't a best idea. Actually we flight from Kharkov to Vienna in reverse direction from Bangkok, so then we should fly 10 hours to Bangkok.</p>

<h1>Running a few step forward.</h1>

<p>Later I use <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a> again to search for and book tickets to Ko Samui from Bangkok. There was a lot of problems with booking tickets with <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a>. so I don't recommend to book tickets with <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a> itself, use it only for searching.</p>

<p>Problems was:</p>

<ul>
<li>They confirm booking</li>
<li>HOLD money on creditcard</li>
<li>Then canceled booking</li>
<li>Money on creditcard stayed on HOLD for 30 days</li>
</ul>


<p>I especially don't like the last point.</p>

<p>I booked tickets that <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a> cannot book for me on site of air company that make flight - it was <a href="http://www.bangkokair.com/eng">Bangkok Airways</a>, there wasn't any problems.</p>

<p>So I got the air tickets, and now <a href="/blog/2013/01/19/winter-in-thailand-or-from-idea-to-reality-part-iii-visas/">I needed to get visa to Thailand.</a></p>

<h1>Further reading</h1>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.orbitz.com/">Orbitz</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Winter in Thailand or from idea to reality: Part I - Why Thailand?]]></title>
    <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2012/11/20/winter-in-thailand-or-from-idea-to-reality-part-i-why-thailand/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-20T22:09:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2012/11/20/winter-in-thailand-or-from-idea-to-reality-part-i-why-thailand</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Introduction</h1>

<p>I want to write several articles about living Thailand. Of course a lot of people have been there, so my articles could look a little trite, but, on the other hand - why not? May be my experience will be useful for somebody.</p>

<h1>About remote work and living in foreign countries</h1>

<p>Many of remote workers can easily work everywhere if there's an fair internet connection. If you like to travel - mix travel and work look like a very attractive idea.</p>

<p>When you are on usual holiday you hardly learn a lot about foreign country during those two weeks. But if you live and work in there for several month - Oh you can tell a lot about it.</p>

<p>Also different places of world have different features, may be you'll like some of them.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h1>Why Thailand?</h1>

<p>I like weather to be warm. I like sea, fruits and learning foreign languages. Also I'm a remote worker, so I need fair internet connection.</p>

<p>As winter begin to come - I thought, may be it'd be great to move to some warm place? I'm not rich DevOp from Ukraine so this place should have prices comparable with Ukraine ones.</p>

<p>So after some comparision and reading different sources I choose Thailand. How it looks from internet?</p>

<p>Pros:</p>

<ul>
<li>it's cheap to live here, about the same prices as living costs in Ukraine.</li>
<li>A lot of tasty and fresh fruits, vegetables and seafood.</li>
<li>Sea available</li>
<li>It's warm here, no winter at all</li>
<li>Crime rates are low, people are friendly and positive.</li>
<li>Internet is good, mostly ADSL as wired connection and also there's a several 3G operators with good coverage.</li>
</ul>


<p>Cons:</p>

<ul>
<li>A lot of insects here</li>
<li>It's a little too hot here</li>
<li>a few people in Thailand speak english, you will need to learn Thai to have full living experience here.</li>
</ul>


<p>Running ahead, I should tell that all these stuff appear to be true, when I've come to Thailand.</p>

<p>It looks good for me - so I choose Thailand, that lead me to next step:</p>

<h1>Thailand is big, where to go?</h1>

<p>We need:</p>

<ul>
<li>sea around</li>
<li>some infrastructure (water, electricity, internet and so on)</li>
<li>it would be great if place wasn't noisy - so we could work without disturbances.</li>
<li>not very expensive to live</li>
</ul>


<p>Candidates:</p>

<p>After some investigation about Thailand I choose several places to go.</p>

<h2>Koh Samui</h2>

<ul>
<li>pros:

<ul>
<li>good beaches</li>
<li>serene place</li>
<li>it's romantic to live on the tropical island</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>cons:

<ul>
<li>small island, so not so much infrastructure (supermarkets are still here though)</li>
<li>more expensive than (for example) Bangkok</li>
<li>on some parts of island internet is not very good</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2>Hua Hin:</h2>

<ul>
<li>pros:

<ul>
<li>internet is better than on islands.</li>
<li>prices are decent.</li>
<li>good beaches.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>cons:</li>
</ul>


<h2>Phuket:</h2>

<ul>
<li>pros:

<ul>
<li>medium island with bridge to continent, easy to go somewhere</li>
<li>You'll still live on tropical island</li>
<li>relatively good internet</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>cons:

<ul>
<li>more expensive than Samui (which's not very cheap!)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2>Krabi</h2>

<ul>
<li>pros:

<ul>
<li>good beaches</li>
<li>there're good climbing sites (I like climbing)</li>
<li>good for snorkeling (I like snorkeling too)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>cons:

<ul>
<li>more expensive than Samui (which's not very cheap!)</li>
<li>internet isn't very good there</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2>Pattaya</h2>

<ul>
<li>pros:

<ul>
<li>good infrastructure (internet, super markets and so on)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>cons:

<ul>
<li>noisy and messy place, a lot of night life</li>
<li>it's expensive to live there</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>After some thoughts I decided to go to Koh Samui, I like serene places, and it's not too expensive to live there. May be I'll try Hua Hin next year.</p>

<p>So now I know where to go, that lead me to the next step - <a href="/blog/2012/12/15/winter-in-thailand-or-from-idea-to-reality-part-ii-air-tickets/">I needed to buy air tickets to Thailand.</a></p>

<h1>Further reading</h1>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_cities_in_Thailand">List of cities in Thailand</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.thaivisa.com/forum/">Big forum about Thailand</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.thaivisa.com/forum/forum/30-koh-samui-koh-phangan-koh-tao/">Section of Big forum about Thailand, Koh Samui island</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
