<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: visa | DevOp's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/blog/categories/visa/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-18T19:51:54+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://jakshi.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[jakshi]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Winter in Thailand or from idea to reality: Part III - Visas]]></title>
    <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2013/01/19/winter-in-thailand-or-from-idea-to-reality-part-iii-visas/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-19T23:31:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2013/01/19/winter-in-thailand-or-from-idea-to-reality-part-iii-visas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Intro</h1>

<p>I have air tickets to Thailand now, but that's not all. Now I need visa to Thailand.</p>

<p>I will tell about getting visa to Thailand for Ukrainian citizens.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h1>Types of Thailand visas for Ukrainians</h1>

<ul>
<li>Visa on arrival, 15 days: you can get it in the airport. Sometimes you can be asked to prove that you have enough money and have air ticket from Thailand.</li>
<li>Single entry tourist visa, 2 monthes + can be prolong for 1 month for 1900 Baht: You need to process it in advance.</li>
<li>Double entry tourist visa, 2+1 monthes, fly out of Thailand, fly back and then again 2+1 monthes.: You need to process it in advance.</li>
<li>Business visa: about 1 year, I don't look into this visa a lot becasue you need to have some buisness in Thailand.</li>
<li>Education visa: about 1 year, Nod bad, but you need to learn something in Thailand and pay money to some Thailand's educational institution.</li>
</ul>


<h1>Which visa to choose?</h1>

<ul>
<li>Visa to arrival? definitely no, we need to stay for several monthes.</li>
<li>Tourist visa? Sounds good.</li>
<li>Buisness visa? I haven't buisness in Thailand and don't plan to create one.</li>
<li>Education visa? not bad, but more expensive than tourist visa (from 20000 Baht per year). And of course you will need spend time for learning.</li>
</ul>


<p>So after some thoughts I chose double entry tourist's visa.</p>

<h1>Processing a visa</h1>

<p>I do a little trick for proccess Thailand visa easier - I outsource this work to Travel Agency :)
Of course each visa cost more for me(170$ instead of 90$), but I saved a lot of time and brain cells.</p>

<p>Also Travel Agency help us with processing medical insurrance for Thailand, it costs us about 150$ per person.</p>

<p>I provided following documents to process visas:
- Foreign passport
- Reference about your bank account state (you need to have more than 600$ on your bank account)
- Printed air tickets
- Insurance vouchers
- Reference from work that we have work place in Ukraine
- two 3x4 cm photos</p>

<p>I gave these documents to travel agency and in a week have my foreign passports with visa back.</p>

<p>if you proccess double-entry visas usually you need to provide airticket to Thailand and back for both entries. I didn't have tickets for flying out of Thailand after 3 month (first part of double entry visa). I plan to decide later where to go. Luckily Travel agency where I proccessed visas resolve this for me, they booked additional tickets, get the visa for me and then cancel additional tickets. So I don't need to think about <where to travel after 3 month in Thailand>  beforehand. As I got actually you can even don't buy return ticket if you use travel agency service for proccess visas.</p>

<p>Okey, now I have our airticket, I have visa.</p>

<p>So I need to think thorougly which stuff to get with us, and even more thourougly which stuff don't. I need to plan the travel, book hotel and gather info about how to live good in Thailand. I need prepare for trip.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
