<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: air tickets | DevOp's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/blog/categories/air-tickets/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-11T14:21:33+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://jakshi.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[jakshi]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Winter in Thailand or from idea to reality: Part II - Air tickets]]></title>
    <link href="http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/winter-in-thailand-or-from-idea-to-reality-part-ii-air-tickets/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-15T13:02:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jakshi.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/winter-in-thailand-or-from-idea-to-reality-part-ii-air-tickets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Intro</h1>

<p>So I need to buy air tickets to Thailand. After some thoughts we decide to buy air tickets to Bagkok, spent there several days, and then move to Ko Samui.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h1>Where to find cheapest ones?</h1>

<p>I doubt that I'll say something new, but earlier you buy tickets - the cheaper they will get.
Because:</p>

<ul>
<li>most cheap tickets end up first.</li>
<li>most companies give you discount if you buy tickets in advance.</li>
</ul>


<p>Also you can try to search on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_low-cost_airlines">sites of low cost airways</a>, but this will need much more thorough planning of your trip, because low cost airlines are less agile then usual airlines.</p>

<p>Example of low cost airways for Thailand: <a href="http://www.airasia.com/my/en/home.page">AirAsia</a> or <a href="http://www.nokair.com/nokconnext/aspx/Index.aspx?currlang=en-US">NokAir</a>.</p>

<p>I use <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a> to search for cheapest tickets. I bought tickets not early, so they cost me a lot - 900$ per person from Ukraine to Thailand and back.</p>

<p>After I found tickets on <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a>, <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a> provide me a choice of sites where I can book them.</p>

<p>I choose <a href="http://www.orbitz.com/">Orbitz</a>. it was a good choice. <a href="http://www.orbitz.com/">Orbitz</a> worked very well, there wasn't any problems.</p>

<p>I bought tickets from Austrian Airways from Khrakov to Bangkok with one connection in Vienna.</p>

<p>Flight from Kharkov to Vienna was very good. Flight from Vienna to Bangkok in Boing 777 wasn't so comfortable. They have very small chairs in those Boing 777 :)</p>

<p>btw For Ukrainian traveler there's a good route to fly to Dubai, and then fly from Dubai to Bangkok. Looking back I see that idea with connection in Vienna wasn't a best idea. Actually we flight from Kharkov to Vienna in reverse direction from Bangkok, so then we should fly 10 hours to Bangkok.</p>

<h1>Running a few step forward.</h1>

<p>Later I use <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a> again to search for and book tickets to Ko Samui from Bangkok. There was a lot of problems with booking tickets with <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a>. so I don't recommend to book tickets with <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a> itself, use it only for searching.</p>

<p>Problems was:</p>

<ul>
<li>They confirm booking</li>
<li>HOLD money on creditcard</li>
<li>Then canceled booking</li>
<li>Money on creditcard stayed on HOLD for 30 days</li>
</ul>


<p>I especially don't like the last point.</p>

<p>I booked tickets that <a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a> cannot book for me on site of air company that make flight - it was <a href="http://www.bangkokair.com/eng">Bangkok Airways</a>, there wasn't any problems.</p>

<p>So I got the air tickets, and now <a href="/blog/2013/01/19/winter-in-thailand-or-from-idea-to-reality-part-iii-visas/">I needed to get visa to Thailand.</a></p>

<h1>Further reading</h1>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.kayak.com/">KAYAK</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.orbitz.com/">Orbitz</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
